Federico Skrzypicki

(347) 207.1393 ·skrfederico@gmail.com_· Los Angeles, CA · https://www.linkedin.com/in/federicoskrzypicki/·

A full-stack software engineer and entrepreneurial educator with 15+ years of experience across multiple countries and business domains eager to leverage my customer-centric product and business development skills to deliver high-value exceptional products.

SKILLS

Python | JavaScript | MongoDB | PostgreSQL | Express.js | Node.js | Mongoose | Postman | React.js

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Leaders English Institute, Product Manager (remote)

July 2019 - Present

- Successfully increased the YoY revenue by 21% by leading a workplace expansion initiative.
- Increased project completion rates by 40% by recruiting and coaching 28 team members.
- Handled, prioritized, and problem-solved multiple tasks connected to multiple projects at one time.
- Provided regular weekly reports to stakeholders on project progress and health.

East Harlem Tutorial Program, MultiLingual Learner Specialist

October 2021 - July 2022

- Ensured 18 learners reach goals outlined in individualized success plans.
- Acted as a liaison between internal and external stakeholders and managed program operations

The Fluffy Cloud, Project manager

April 2019 - September 2019

- Managed 3 different international teams of 6/8 building and transporting a large scale art installation to Black Rock City.
- Responsible for scheduling, budgeting, accounting, coaching/training, and resource management.
- Consistently met deadlines and received commendations for 6 consecutive months.

Leaders English Institute

February 2010 - June 2019

Product Manager and Director (January 2017 - June 2019) General Coordinator and Director (January 2013 - December 2016) Founder and Teacher (February 2010 - December 2012)

- Analyzed and then effectively strategized in regard to business goals, deadlines, schedules, budgets, needed resources, and team coordination.
- Implemented 1 new program per year to expand the school's offerings and reach, and maintained an average student retention rate of over 90% throughout my tenure
- Leveraged expertise in product management to optimize workflows, leverage data insights, and drive continuous improvement
- Promoted to Coordinator and oversaw operations of the school
- Hired, trained, and supervised a staff of 25 to provide high-quality education and services to students
- Implemented strategies to attract and retain over 150 students through a successful yearly subscription program
- Managed finances, logistics, and customer service to ensure a smooth operation
- Started a School of English as a Second Language overseeing the entire project lifecycle from inception to delivery, and exceeding expectations on time and budget.
- Taught English classes, developed course curriculum and monitored student progress maintaining consistent communication with parents through email, reports, and phone calls.
- Attracted first batch of students and built a solid reputation for the school

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

November 2022 - April 2023

Software Engineering Immersive Flex

UMSA (Universidad del Museo Social Argentino)

English / Spanish Conference Interpreter (Major)

- English / Spanish Literary Translator (Minor)